Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Echoes of the Self]
[أصداء الذات]
Prince Yan, are you growing roots at Zhou's Mansion?
الأمير يان، هل تنمو جذورك في قصر تشو؟
Why are you always here?
لماذا أنت هنا دائما؟
Ever since you decided to return to Zhou's Mansion,
منذ أن قررت العودة إلى قصر تشو،
I've been restless.
لقد كنت مضطربًا.
So,
لذا،
after much consideration,
بعد الكثير من التفكير،
I had to ask Father
كان علي أن أسأل الأب
for an imperial decree of marriage.
للحصول على مرسوم إمبراطوري بالزواج.
With you as my future princess consort,
معك كزوجة الأميرة المستقبلية،
I can protect you fully.
أستطيع حمايتك بشكل كامل.
I never expected
لم اتوقع ابدا
to arrive just in time for this forced marriage drama.
للوصول في الوقت المناسب لهذه الدراما المتعلقة بالزواج القسري.
I should have known all along that Zhou Kui's
كان ينبغي لي أن أعرف منذ البداية أن تشو كوي
sudden move to make me the Zhou family’s principal daughter
خطوة مفاجئة لجعلي الابنة الرئيسية لعائلة تشو
couldn't be so simple.
لا يمكن أن يكون الأمر بهذه البساطة.
But I didn't expect
ولكنني لم اتوقع
he would use this marriage to challenge me
سوف يستخدم هذا الزواج لتحديني
and make me his stepping stone.
واجعلني حجر عثرة له.
That's perfect then.
هذا مثالي إذن.
By a twist of fate...
بسبب تطور القدر...
It worked in my favor.
لقد نجح الأمر لصالحى.
Fu Wei.
فو وي.
Are you ready to become my princess consort?
هل أنت مستعدة لتصبحي زوجتي الأميرة؟
Yan.
نعم.
Why do you have gray hair?
لماذا لديك شعر رمادي؟
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
People
الناس
all grow old.
الجميع يكبرون في السن.
Let's think about
دعونا نفكر في
our wedding.
حفل زفافنا.
About our wedding,
عن حفل زفافنا،
the betrothal gifts,
هدايا الخطوبة،
the wedding wine,
نبيذ الزفاف
and your wedding dress -
وفستان زفافك
nothing can be overlooked.
لا يمكن التغاضي عن أي شيء.
And also...
و أيضا...
Let me think...
دعني أفكر...
[Deep Roots; Lush Branches]
[جذور عميقة؛ فروع خصبة]
Prince Yan, please wait.
الأمير يان، من فضلك انتظر.
Li Yan,
لي يان,
I command you to stop.
أنا آمرك بالتوقف.
Crown Princess,
ولي العهد،
what can I do for you?
ما الذي يمكنني أن أفعله من أجلك؟
Do you hate me that much?
هل تكرهني لهذه الدرجة؟
You should know
ينبغي عليك أن تعرف
everything I've done
كل ما فعلته
was beyond my control.
كان خارجا عن سيطرتي.
Beyond your control?
خارج سيطرتك؟
No matter how much it was beyond your control,
بغض النظر عن مدى خروج الأمر عن سيطرتك،
you shouldn't have warmed yourself with others' blood.
لا ينبغي لك أن تدفئ نفسك بدماء الآخرين.
It seems
يبدو أنه
he knows I'm the real Zhou Ruoxi.
إنه يعرف أنني تشو روكسي الحقيقي.
You're absolutely right.
أنت على حق تماما.
But you should understand
ولكن يجب عليك أن تفهم
that it is I
أنه أنا
who am now the Princess of Daqing.
من أنا الآن أميرة داتشينغ.
The position of Crown Princess
منصب ولي العهد
is also mine.
وهي لي أيضا.
Please help me pick it up.
من فضلك ساعدني في التقاطه.
I said,
قلت
[Deep Roots; Lush Branches]
[جذور عميقة؛ فروع خصبة]
Thank you, Prince Yan.
شكرا لك الأمير يان.
How did the Eastern Palace token
كيف تم إنشاء رمز القصر الشرقي؟
end up in her hands?
ينتهي في يديها؟
What is she planning to do?
ماذا تخطط أن تفعل؟
Mother died tragically because of the loan sharking case.
توفيت الأم بشكل مأساوي بسبب قضية قرض الفوائد الباهظة.
In Zhou's Mansion,
في قصر تشو،
there's evidence of Father's corruption and graft.
هناك أدلة على فساد الأب والرشوة.
It seems Father was the mastermind behind the loan sharking case.
يبدو أن الأب كان العقل المدبر وراء قضية القروض الربوية.
But Cui Yuan'an came to assassinate the Crown Prince,
لكن كوي يوان آن جاء لاغتيال ولي العهد،
claiming with certainty that he was behind the loan sharking case.
مدعيا على وجه اليقين أنه كان وراء قضية القروض الربوية.
No matter who it is,
بغض النظر عمن هو،
I must find out the truth
يجب أن أكتشف الحقيقة
and avenge my mother.
وانتقم لأمي.
[Prince Yan's Mansion]
[قصر الأمير يان]
I remember my brother
أتذكر أخي
once sent someone with the Eastern Palace token
لقد أرسلت ذات مرة لشخص ما رمز القصر الشرقي
to investigate troop stockpiling in the black market.
للتحقيق في تخزين القوات في السوق السوداء.
After that, the spies who were sent went missing,
وبعد ذلك اختفى الجواسيس الذين تم إرسالهم،
so the matter was dropped.
لذلك تم إسقاط الموضوع.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
The token you asked me to investigate
الرمز الذي طلبت مني التحقيق فيه
was last seen in the black market.
شوهد آخر مرة في السوق السوداء.
It was mainly involved in
لقد شاركت بشكل رئيسي في
arms and ordnance transportation.
نقل الأسلحة والذخائر.
The black market again.
السوق السوداء مرة أخرى
The money confiscated
الأموال المصادرة
from the Marquis of Zhenguo's Mansion
من قصر ماركيز تشنغو
has huge discrepancies with what's recorded in the ledger.
يوجد تناقضات كبيرة مع ما هو مسجل في الدفتر.
The final lead
الرصاص النهائي
also ends at the black market.
وينتهي أيضًا في السوق السوداء.
Could all this money
هل يمكن أن يكون كل هذا المال
have been used to secretly stockpile arms and ordnance?
هل تم استخدامها لتخزين الأسلحة والذخائر سراً؟
Could it be as Fu Wei suspects,
هل يمكن أن يكون الأمر كما يشتبه فو وي؟
that the one who has dealings with the Daqing royal family
أن الشخص الذي لديه تعاملات مع العائلة المالكة داتشينغ
and manipulates everything behind the scenes
ويتلاعب بكل شيء خلف الكواليس
is my brother?
هو أخي؟
Shu.
هذا كل شيء.
Black market.
السوق السوداء.
Arms and ordnance transportation.
نقل الأسلحة والذخائر.
What exactly is he planning to do?
ماذا يخطط للقيام به بالضبط؟
Rebellion.
تمرد.
The Crown Prince is planning a rebellion.
ولي العهد يخطط للتمرد.
Get out.
اخرج.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Did I...
هل فعلت...؟
Say something wrong?
هل تقول شيئا خاطئا؟
The door is there.
الباب هناك.
Get out.
اخرج.
Yes.
نعم.
Shu is already the future heir.
شو هو بالفعل الوريث المستقبلي.
He would never commit treason.
لن يرتكب الخيانة أبدًا.
Who is it that schemes with such intent,
من هو الذي يخطط بهذه النية؟
controlling everything from the shadows?
السيطرة على كل شيء من الظلال؟
Master.
يتقن.
I wonder what orders you have in summoning me here
أتساءل ما هي الأوامر التي لديك في استدعائي هنا
at this late hour.
في هذه الساعة المتأخرة.
Lord Zhou?
اللورد تشو؟
Find an opportunity
ابحث عن فرصة
to enter the palace
للدخول إلى القصر
and meet with that person inside
والالتقاء بهذا الشخص في الداخل
to retrieve something for me.
لأستعيد شيئاً ما بالنسبة لي.
Yes.
نعم.
Master.
يتقن.
Crown Princess.
ولي العهد.
Why aren't you helping me change my clothes?
لماذا لا تساعدني في تغيير ملابسي؟
I'm going to the palace today.
سأذهب إلى القصر اليوم.
Crown Princess,
ولي العهد،
come with me.
تعال معي.
Previously,
سابقًا،
I misunderstood you.
لقد اساءت فهمك.
Please forgive me.
رجائاً أعطني.
As for you,
أما بالنسبة لك،
you've been married into the Eastern Palace for some time now.
لقد كنت متزوجا من القصر الشرقي لبعض الوقت الآن.
You should pay respects to the royal ladies in the palace,
يجب عليك تقديم الاحترام للسيدات الملكيات في القصر،
otherwise it would be disrespectful.
وإلا فسيكون ذلك عدم احترام.
I will
أنا سوف
prepare right away.
استعد على الفور.
For now,
في الوقت الراهن،
I can only make good use of her, the substitute,
لا أستطيع إلا أن أستفيد منها بشكل جيد، كبديل،
and find clues through her.
وإيجاد الأدلة من خلالها.
His Majesty has invited the Crown Prince and Prince Yan for a meeting.
وقد دعا جلالته ولي العهد والأمير يان للقاء.
Miss Zhou Ruoxi, you may wait here.
السيدة تشو روكسي، يمكنك الانتظار هنا.
Greetings, Your Highness.
تحياتي، صاحب السمو.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Li Shu.
لي شو.
If all this is related to you,
إذا كان كل هذا يتعلق بك،
I won't let you get away with it.
لن أسمح لك بالهرب من ذلك.
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
The Crown Prince is here.
ولي العهد هنا.
Father.
أب.
Where is the Crown Princess?
أين ولي العهد؟
She brought some gifts
لقد جلبت بعض الهدايا
and went to pay respects to the ladies in the inner palace.
وذهب لتقديم الاحترام للسيدات في القصر الداخلي.
You two were recently married.
لقد تزوجتما مؤخرا.
Are you getting along well?
هل أنت على ما يرام؟
It's a marriage bestowed by you, Father.
إنه زواج ممنوح منك يا أبي.
And it's an alliance between two countries.
وهو تحالف بين بلدين.
I will certainly treat the Crown Princess
سأعالج ولي العهد بالتأكيد
with the utmost care and affection.
مع أقصى درجات العناية والمودة.
You're husband and wife,
أنت زوج وزوجة
and newlyweds at that.
والمتزوجين حديثًا أيضًا.
Why speak so distantly?
لماذا نتحدث عن مسافة بعيدة؟
I summoned you to the palace today
لقد دعوتك إلى القصر اليوم
to discuss
لمناقشة
your brother's marriage.
زواج أخيك.
Shu.
هذا كل شيء.
Father
أب
has arranged my marriage to Miss Zhou Ruoxi,
لقد رتب زواجي من الآنسة تشو رووكسي،
and we will be married soon.
وسوف نتزوج قريبا.
I hope you will
أتمنى أن تفعل ذلك
find time to attend our wedding.
إيجاد الوقت لحضور حفل زفافنا.
Miss Zhou Ruoxi?
الآنسة تشو Ruoxi؟
Yes.
نعم.
Wasn't Yan
ألم يكن يان
in love with Princess Fu Wei before?
هل كنت تحب الأميرة فو وي من قبل؟
Why did he agree to this marriage so readily?
لماذا وافق على هذا الزواج بهذه السهولة؟
Marrying Miss Zhou Ruoxi
الزواج من الآنسة تشو Ruoxi
is Father's decree.
هو قرار الأب.
This is my duty as his subject.
هذا واجبي كموضوع له.
Yan.
نعم.
Yes,
نعم،
Father.
أب.
I previously
انا سابقا
arranged for the Princess of Daqing
تم الترتيب لأميرة داتشينغ
to marry your brother.
الزواج من أخيك.
I know you were upset about it.
أعرف أنك كنت مستاءً بشأن هذا الأمر.
But now
ولكن الان
you have someone you care for too.
لديك شخص تهتم به أيضًا.
From now on, there should be
من الآن فصاعدا، ينبغي أن يكون هناك
no more conflicts between you brothers over such matters.
لا مزيد من الصراعات بينكم أيها الإخوة حول مثل هذه الأمور.
Shu.
هذا كل شيء.
You must attend
يجب عليك الحضور
Yan's wedding ceremony
حفل زفاف يان
to add to your brother's happiness.
لتضيف إلى سعادة أخيك.
Rest assured, Father.
اطمئن يا أبي.
I will certainly give Yan
سأعطي يان بالتأكيد
a grand gift.
هدية عظيمة.
Linglan?
لينغلان؟
Here's what His Highness requested.
وهذا ما طلبه سموه:
Our path has been cut off.
لقد تم قطع طريقنا.
We had no choice but to ask for your help.
لم يكن أمامنا خيار سوى أن نطلب مساعدتكم.
His Highness?
صاحب السمو؟
Fu Wei.
فو وي.
Father has agreed to attend the wedding ceremony.
وافق الأب على حضور حفل الزفاف.
I believe on our wedding day,
أعتقد أنه في يوم زفافنا،
it will be extremely lively.
ستكون حيوية للغاية.
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
Is there something wrong?
هل هناك شيء خاطئ؟
If there's anything,
إذا كان هناك أي شيء،
you can't hide it from me.
لا يمكنك إخفاء ذلك عني.
I just can't figure some things out.
لا أستطيع فهم بعض الأشياء.
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
Are you hiding anything from me?
هل تخفي عني شيئا؟
What could I possibly hide from you?
ماذا يمكنني أن أخفيه عنك؟
You know
أنت تعرف
more than anyone else here.
أكثر من أي شخص آخر هنا.
What's the price of extending life with the Seven-Star Lamp?
ما هو ثمن تمديد الحياة باستخدام مصباح النجوم السبعة؟
Did you use your own lifespan
هل استخدمت عمرك الافتراضي؟
to extend mine?
لتمديد لي؟
Thank you, Doctor, for extending my life.
شكرا لك يا دكتور على تمديد حياتي.
There's something I don't understand.
هناك شيئا لا أفهمه.
What is the price of extending life with the Seven-Star Lamp?
ما هو ثمن تمديد الحياة باستخدام مصباح النجوم السبعة؟
Does it
هل يفعل ذلك؟
harm others?
إيذاء الآخرين؟
Everything
كل شئ
has its price.
له ثمنه.
To gain something,
للحصول على شيء ما،
something must be lost.
لا بد من فقدان شيء ما.
Is there any way to undo it?
هل هناك أي طريقة للتراجع عن ذلك؟
I don't want Prince Yan to sacrifice for me.
لا أريد أن يضحي الأمير يان من أجلي.
What can I do?
ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل؟
I'm willing to pay any price.
أنا مستعد لدفع أي ثمن.
There is no way to reverse it.
لا توجد طريقة لعكس ذلك.
Miss,
يفتقد،
live in the present
العيش في الحاضر
and cherish who you have now.
واعتز بمن لديك الآن.
Fu Wei.
فو وي.
I have something to tell you.
عندي شيء أريد أن أخبرك به.
Wonton!
وونتون!
Noodle soup!
حساء المعكرونة!
Candied haws!
الزعرور المسكر!
Hya!
يا!
Where are you taking me?
إلى أين تأخذني؟
I've got something new
لقد حصلت على شيء جديد
that I want to show you.
الذي أريد أن أعرضه لك.
Right here.
هنا.
Look.
ينظر.
One easily knows the face of the east wind;
من السهل معرفة وجه الريح الشرقية؛
In a thousand shades of purple and red,
بألف لون من الأرجواني والأحمر،
all is spring.
كل شيء ربيع.
Green trees cast deep shade as summer days grow long;
تُلقي الأشجار الخضراء بظلالها العميقة مع طول أيام الصيف؛
Pavilions reflect their forms
الأجنحة تعكس أشكالها
within the pond.
داخل البركة.
Maple leaves turn the mountains crimson bright;
أوراق القيقب تحول الجبال إلى اللون القرمزي الساطع؛
Yellow blossoms
أزهار صفراء
endure the evening breeze.
تحمل نسيم المساء.
Who plays the flute in heaven, none can tell;
من يعزف على الناي في السماء لا أحد يستطيع أن يعرف؛
Snowflakes drift
انجراف رقاقات الثلج
and blanket all the world.
وتغطي العالم كله.
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter,
الربيع والصيف والخريف والشتاء
each season holds its charm.
كل موسم له سحره.
But without you,
ولكن بدونك،
everything loses its luster.
كل شيء يفقد بريقه
Between us,
بيننا،
let's not speak of debts.
دعونا لا نتحدث عن الديون.
Of all things in this world,
من بين كل الأشياء في هذا العالم،
as long as we're together,
طالما نحن معا،
that alone
هذا وحده
is enough.
يكفي.
Linglan?
لينغلان؟
She isn't serving the Crown Princess
إنها لا تخدم ولي العهد
but has come to Zhou's Mansion—what for?
ولكنه جاء إلى قصر تشو - لماذا؟
[Pass for the Military Supply Route]
[تصريح لطريق الإمداد العسكري]
Military Supply Route?
طريق الامداد العسكري؟
This is what His Highness requested.
وهذا ما طلبه سموه.
What do they need this pass for?
لماذا يحتاجون هذا المرور؟
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
Linglan,
لينغلان،
whose side are you really on?
من هو الجانب الذي أنت فيه حقا؟
Since you're here,
بما أنك هنا،
why not meet me openly,
لماذا لا تلتقي بي علانية؟
Princess Fu Wei?
الأميرة فو وي؟